<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>basepi</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://basepi.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://basepi.github.io/</id><updated>2018-05-23T13:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>HubbleStack on FLOSS Weekly</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2018/05/hubblestack-on-floss-weekly/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-23T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T13:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2018-05-23:/2018/05/hubblestack-on-floss-weekly/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was on &lt;a href="https://twit.tv/shows/floss-weekly"&gt;FLOSS Weekly&lt;/a&gt; today talking about HubbleStack!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/+B1kASMk0Y"&gt;Overcast link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you really want to see my ugly mug, there are video options as well on the episode page: &lt;a href="https://twit.tv/shows/floss-weekly/episodes/485?autostart=false"&gt;FLOSS Weekly 485 HubbleStack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about HubbleStack or want to get involved, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/basepi"&gt;tweet at …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was on &lt;a href="https://twit.tv/shows/floss-weekly"&gt;FLOSS Weekly&lt;/a&gt; today talking about HubbleStack!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/+B1kASMk0Y"&gt;Overcast link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you really want to see my ugly mug, there are video options as well on the episode page: &lt;a href="https://twit.tv/shows/floss-weekly/episodes/485?autostart=false"&gt;FLOSS Weekly 485 HubbleStack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about HubbleStack or want to get involved, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/basepi"&gt;tweet at me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Value of Diversity</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2018/03/the-value-of-diversity/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-05T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-03-05T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2018-03-05:/2018/03/the-value-of-diversity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts"&gt;an ex-Google recruiter sued Google for wrongful termination due to his
complaints about hiring practices he claimed were discriminatory against white
and Asian
men.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us have been in positions where hiring for diversity has been a focus.
There might be a temptation to say that this is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2018/03/ex-google-recruiter-i-was-fired-because-i-resisted-illegal-diversity-efforts"&gt;an ex-Google recruiter sued Google for wrongful termination due to his
complaints about hiring practices he claimed were discriminatory against white
and Asian
men.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us have been in positions where hiring for diversity has been a focus.
There might be a temptation to say that this is discriminatory. "We're passing
up more qualified candidates for diverse ones!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But diversity is about more than skin color or gender -- it's also about the
different ideas and points of view that come from different life experiences.
These are real qualifications. Their value-add is hard to quantify, but that
doesn't mean the value isn't there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding these people is not easy. We have to be willing to go outside our
normal networks. And even once we find and hire these people we have to work
hard to overcome biases and give them an equal place in our team, both in pay
and in voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring managers can fix the pay gap. Offer people what they're worth, even if
that means countering with a &lt;em&gt;higher&lt;/em&gt; offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voice is harder -- make sure credit is attributed correctly for all team
members. Watch for interruptions from other team members. Make sure everyone is
heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring and keeping diverse people is hard work but it's worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Gun Violence</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2017/10/gun-violence/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-05T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-10-05T13:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2017-10-05:/2017/10/gun-violence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the risk of joining the echo chamber, I want to talk for a moment about gun
violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don't want to talk about criminal gun violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/gun-deaths/"&gt;Start here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click through that graph. See the red dots? Those are suicides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the 33,000 gun deaths annually in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the risk of joining the echo chamber, I want to talk for a moment about gun
violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don't want to talk about criminal gun violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/gun-deaths/"&gt;Start here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click through that graph. See the red dots? Those are suicides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the 33,000 gun deaths annually in America are suicides. That's
more than 20,000 people killing themselves annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why I want to talk about gun control. I believe it would also reduce
gun-related homicides and accidental gun deaths, a result that would also be
amazing. But they're much harder to argue about because we don't have enough
data and there are too many guns in circulation and blah blah blah blah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to reduce the number of suicides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT COLTON, PEOPLE DON'T NEED GUNS TO KILL THEMSELVES. THEY'LL FIND A WAY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are many other ways people can kill themselves besides guns,
readily-available guns offer the least friction. There's no roap to tie,
there's no stool to fetch, there's no blade and bathtub. Pull the trigger and
you're done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we know that removing means of suicide coincides with a drop in suicide
rates. Why is this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's because most people don't really want to die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They're looking for an excuse to live. Any excuse. They're lazy, like you and
me and everyone else. If it's hard to commit suicide, they'll talk themselves
out of it. Every minute of delay from the point of decision improves their
chances of survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an aspect of suicide I had never considered until I listened to &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/+FboE1Ol8k/18:04"&gt;a
podcast&lt;/a&gt; on the subject. It's called
means reduction and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if gun control didn't lower the instances of criminal gun use (though I'm
convinced it would), wouldn't it be worthwhile to save thousands of lives lost
to suicide or accidental death? Shouldn't it at least be a conversation? Are
your guns really that important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not necessarily saying we need a complete gun ban. It's a bit of a
non-starter and I don't think it would ever happen in the US. But there are
things we could do to add friction and insight into firearm acquisition that
could make a real difference. But first we have to have a more cogent
conversation than the normal "BUT LIVES!" "BUT 2ND AMMENDMENT!" bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Karabiner (Elements) and macOS Sierra</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2017/06/karabiner-elements-and-macos-sierra/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-14T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-06-14T13:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2017-06-14:/2017/06/karabiner-elements-and-macos-sierra/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like hacks. I like tweaks. I like setting things up just to my
specifications. I mean, I use an &lt;a href="https://input.club/devices/infinity-ergodox/"&gt;Ergodox
Infinity&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="http://clearlysuperiortech.com/cst2545-5wproductpage.html"&gt;CST
Trackball&lt;/a&gt; and I'm
an &lt;a href="https://github.com/basepi/dotfiles/blob/master/vim/vimrc"&gt;avid Vim user&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these hacks and tweaks are not without their disadvantages. When macOS
Sierra came out, it severely broke support …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like hacks. I like tweaks. I like setting things up just to my
specifications. I mean, I use an &lt;a href="https://input.club/devices/infinity-ergodox/"&gt;Ergodox
Infinity&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="http://clearlysuperiortech.com/cst2545-5wproductpage.html"&gt;CST
Trackball&lt;/a&gt; and I'm
an &lt;a href="https://github.com/basepi/dotfiles/blob/master/vim/vimrc"&gt;avid Vim user&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these hacks and tweaks are not without their disadvantages. When macOS
Sierra came out, it severely broke support for a key app in my setup:
&lt;a href="https://pqrs.org/osx/karabiner/"&gt;Karabiner&lt;/a&gt;. I was using Karabiner for three
very specific, very important hacks, all inspired by &lt;a href="http://stevelosh.com/blog/2012/10/a-modern-space-cadet/"&gt;Steve Losh's "A Modern
Space Cadet" blog post from
2012&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;ctrl&lt;/code&gt; key would act as &lt;code&gt;escape&lt;/code&gt; if short-pressed with no other key.
   Because I rebind &lt;code&gt;caps lock&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;control&lt;/code&gt; anyway, that puts both &lt;code&gt;control&lt;/code&gt;
   and &lt;code&gt;escape&lt;/code&gt; in perfect reach of my left pinky.  No more reaching up or down
   for either key.  It's amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;F19&lt;/code&gt; was mapped to &lt;code&gt;cmd-ctrl-shift-option&lt;/code&gt;. Why &lt;code&gt;F19&lt;/code&gt;? Because it is on no
   modern keyboard, and has no default usage in modern operating systems. So I
   bound it to a key on my ergodox, and use it as a
   &lt;a href="http://stevelosh.com/blog/2012/10/a-modern-space-cadet/#hyper"&gt;&lt;code&gt;hyper&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   modifier key.  However, I went a step further, and made short presses on
   this key input &lt;code&gt;cmd-space&lt;/code&gt; (the spotlight shortcut). Surprisingly convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The left and right &lt;code&gt;shift&lt;/code&gt; keys would act as left and right parenthesis when
   short-pressed with no other keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These hacks have become second nature, part of my muscle memory. Losing them
would be terrible for my productivity. So I waited for Karabiner to be updated
to Sierra.....cut to today, 9 months after Sierra was released, and Karabiner
still has not been updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I found out today that Karabiner Elements &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://cmsj.net/2017/06/13/karabiner-elements-sierra-hyper.html"&gt;added support for
short vs long pressed
keys&lt;/a&gt; in their
latest beta version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to check out my implementation, I &lt;a href="https://github.com/basepi/dotfiles/blob/master/misc/config/karabiner/karabiner.json"&gt;host my dotfiles on
github&lt;/a&gt;.
The section is under &lt;code&gt;complex_modifications&lt;/code&gt;. Remember that you need to be
running Karabiner Elements 0.91.3, which is in beta!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What hacks/tweaks can you not live without? Leave a comment or &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/basepi"&gt;tweet at
me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Poison</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2016/11/poison/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-11T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T17:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2016-11-11:/2016/11/poison/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I found out that a good friend of mine quit Facebook. I was astounded --
he had just been filled with such righteous indignation about the election, and
big ideas about the change that we needed to bring about. How could he bring
about that change if he removed the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I found out that a good friend of mine quit Facebook. I was astounded --
he had just been filled with such righteous indignation about the election, and
big ideas about the change that we needed to bring about. How could he bring
about that change if he removed the best tool for talking to people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the more we talked, the more convinced I was that he had it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night of the election, &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/yXhFGO8R7aU?t=1m45s"&gt;Stephen Colbert talked about
poison&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You take a little bit of it so you can hate the other side. And it tastes
kind of good. And you like how it feels. And there's a gentle high to the
condemnation, right? And you know you're right, right? You know you're right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media is at the center of this. Facebook is &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; to give you this
high. It is &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; to give you exactly what you want to see/hear, because
that keeps you coming back and lets them serve you more ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We craft echo chambers for ourselves. We are increasingly convinced we are
right and the other side is wrong, and if we ever do happen to come in contact
with someone from the other side, we talk past each other until we're blue in
the face. Anger and indignation prevail, reason and empathy fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last three days I've seen very few productive conversations happening on
social media. We try to empathize, we try to make our points. But without the
human connection of one-on-one communication, we make no progress. We high five
those that agree with us and ignore those who don't. We may not even realize
we're ignoring anyone -- the Facebook algorithm is making that choice for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/11/09/rigged/"&gt;TechCrunch says the Facebook bubble just
popped&lt;/a&gt;. They're right. Read that
story, and realize the dangers of the echo chamber. Facebook does more harm
than good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@mikeplace/election-night-6f900f38bb7b#.ez0pm3y8b"&gt;his last
post&lt;/a&gt;
before quitting Facebook, my friend Mike made some cogent points about our
rejection of fact in favor of our echo chambers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a century of prosperity, we started to believe that we knew better than
what newspapers told us, or scientists told us, or economists told us. We
stopped believing in classical books by great thinkers and started believing in
podcasts. In even the best cases, we fired articles at each other instead of
arguments. What’s more, we thought that our skepticism of expertise was the
fault of the expert and not our own. We built the Internet in hopes that it
would foster the greatest exchange of ideas in human history. Hopes of that
nobility have been diminished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This election is a lot of things but above all, it’s cultural hubris boiled
over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He goes on to talk about our rejection of fact-based media in favor of our
little social media worlds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, we rejected newspapers, nearly bankrupted them and then
wondered what happened to the fourth estate. I’m not so sure that we should be
as outraged as ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite quotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are unwilling to accept facts that do not align with your view of
reality, you are the most dangerous kind of coward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mike doesn't leave us without a call to action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you want to be angry, be angry — for a while, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re done, though, go out and buy a newspaper subscription to every
single publication that you can afford to support. Do this not just for papers
which lean in your direction but any paper which has reputable, hard-working
reporters who are dedicated to shining a light where it needs to shine. Read
all of them. Every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they report the facts, accept them as facts — not as a hypothesis which
has its truth contingent on the institution which presented it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, too, when they editorialize, accept that as opinion from people who
understand the world in a sophisticated way. Admire that sophistication, even
if you do not agree with its conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not conflate facts and opinions. Even if you are wrong five percent of the
time and bias sneaks into reporting, accept it and move on. Stop throwing
babies out with bathwater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, find a friend, if you can, and see where there might be common
ground to stand on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The waters rise fast and we only survive if we hold on to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stronger together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I spent a solid two hours talking to two of my best friends while we
ate tacos after playing basketball. It was a productive, respectful
conversation.  I learned things and grew, and we didn't just talk past each
other. Granted, this was helped by the fact that we have similar views, but it
was refreshing all the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want more of those nights. I want to have smaller, real conversations with
people. I want to learn and grow. I want to be more than just retweets and
likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's my plan: I plan to get back to my subscription to The Economist and
The Washington Post. I plan to read fact-based reporting and editorializing and
form my own opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as importantly, I have to get out of my echo chamber. And I'm less and less
willing to feed into the machine that caused this: Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few days, after most people who will see this post have seen it, I will
likely disable my Facebook account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter is harder. I love Twitter: It's the poison I crave. But I think it has
to go as well, at least for awhile. So I'll be taking a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn't mean that I don't want to talk. In fact, I want to talk more
than ever. But I don't want to do it on Facebook or Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call me. Text me. Let's go grab a drink (soda for me) or some lunch and chat.
Let's make real relationships, and have real conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let's stop drinking the poison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;colton.myers@gmail.com // 801-999-8328&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hate</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2016/11/hate/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-09T14:41:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-09T14:41:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2016-11-09:/2016/11/hate/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trump gave a surprisingly presidential victory speech:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, she fought very hard. Hillary has worked very long and very hard over
a long period of time, and we owe her a major debt of gratitude for her service
to our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean that very sincerely. Now it is …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trump gave a surprisingly presidential victory speech:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, she fought very hard. Hillary has worked very long and very hard over
a long period of time, and we owe her a major debt of gratitude for her service
to our country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean that very sincerely. Now it is time for America to bind the wounds of
division, have to get together. To all Republicans and Democrats and
independents across this nation, I say it is time for us to come together as
one united people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this is the Trump that will enter office as our next president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I'm less worried about Trump as president than I am about the hate,
mistrust, racism, and sexism that his campaign made mainstream. He validated
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/796417517157830656"&gt;monstrous behaviors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read every story in that link. Think about what it would be like to live in
fear of the people around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a straight white male, I'm blessed with safety from acts like this. I will
wield that safety in defense of those who are not. I won't allow casual or
joking racism. If I see someone being harassed, I will step in. I will serve
and love those around me. And I will pray for those who are living in fear
today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you join me?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>American</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2016/11/american/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-08T23:45:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-08T23:45:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2016-11-08:/2016/11/american/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight I am embarrassed to be an American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For much of my life I identified as a Republican. In the last few years I've
found myself identifying less and less with that party. Not to say I'm a
Democrat; both parties have serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I voted for Hillary …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight I am embarrassed to be an American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For much of my life I identified as a Republican. In the last few years I've
found myself identifying less and less with that party. Not to say I'm a
Democrat; both parties have serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I voted for Hillary. Not because she was the lesser of two evils.
She's far from perfect, and I don't agree with her on everything. But she's an
accomplished politician and a qualified presidential candidate. I like the
strength with which she has dealt with Trump's attacks. I voted for her because
I'm With Her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably not a popular opinion. But I'm trying to be true to my
opinions rather than just hiding behind the "Trump is a monster" argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight America chose hate, mistrust, racism, misogyny, and violence. Tonight I
am embarrassed to be an American.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Check Out the Packt Free Learning Campaign!</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2015/02/check-out-the-packt-free-learning-campaign/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-25T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-02-25T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2015-02-25:/2015/02/check-out-the-packt-free-learning-campaign/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Packt is running a cool promotion right now where you can get a different free ebook each day until a March 5. &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/1DoRno5"&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Packt is running a cool promotion right now where you can get a different free ebook each day until a March 5. &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/1DoRno5"&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>My Book is Available!</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2015/01/my-book-is-available/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-28T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-01-28T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2015-01-28:/2015/01/my-book-is-available/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My book, Learning SaltStack, is available for purchase!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's available in &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1784394602/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1784394602&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=basepi-20&amp;amp;linkId=KX45BKGQ7GEWYORT"&gt;paperback&lt;/a&gt;, as well as for &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00SVBFBM2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00SVBFBM2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=basepi-20&amp;amp;linkId=GIWAB2W3FF477ENW"&gt;kindle&lt;/a&gt; from
Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also buy it &lt;a href="https://www.packtpub.com/networking-and-servers/learning-saltstack"&gt;directly from Packt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My book, Learning SaltStack, is available for purchase!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's available in &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1784394602/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1784394602&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=basepi-20&amp;amp;linkId=KX45BKGQ7GEWYORT"&gt;paperback&lt;/a&gt;, as well as for &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00SVBFBM2/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00SVBFBM2&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=basepi-20&amp;amp;linkId=GIWAB2W3FF477ENW"&gt;kindle&lt;/a&gt; from
Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also buy it &lt;a href="https://www.packtpub.com/networking-and-servers/learning-saltstack"&gt;directly from Packt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Mitigating GHOST with SaltStack</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2015/01/mitigating-ghost-with-saltstack/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-27T15:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-01-27T15:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2015-01-27:/2015/01/mitigating-ghost-with-saltstack/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My coworker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/croldham"&gt;CR&lt;/a&gt; wrote up a great guide to mitigating the new &lt;a href="http://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2015/01/27/9"&gt;GHOST
vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://www.saltstack.com"&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out here:
&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@cro/mitigating-ghost-with-salt-2a28b6eb9e4b"&gt;Mitigating GHOST with Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't already checked out SaltStack, I highly recommend it! You'll
never have to manually patch all of your machines again!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My coworker &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/croldham"&gt;CR&lt;/a&gt; wrote up a great guide to mitigating the new &lt;a href="http://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2015/01/27/9"&gt;GHOST
vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://www.saltstack.com"&gt;SaltStack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check it out here:
&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@cro/mitigating-ghost-with-salt-2a28b6eb9e4b"&gt;Mitigating GHOST with Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't already checked out SaltStack, I highly recommend it! You'll
never have to manually patch all of your machines again!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>The Problem with the Hobbit Movies</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2015/01/the-problem-with-the-hobbit-movies/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-03T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-01-03T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2015-01-03:/2015/01/the-problem-with-the-hobbit-movies/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was catching up on my RSS feeds and I found [this review of the last Hobbit
movie by Ars Technica][1]. Sums up my feelings perfectly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's one big thing that doomed these movies from the outset—the fiscally
smart but artistically bankrupt decision to make a single, shortish …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was catching up on my RSS feeds and I found [this review of the last Hobbit
movie by Ars Technica][1]. Sums up my feelings perfectly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's one big thing that doomed these movies from the outset—the fiscally
smart but artistically bankrupt decision to make a single, shortish
children's novel into three feature-length prequel films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artistically bankrupt. Perfect way to put it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What these movies desperately need are boundaries, reasons to condense scenes
or cut them out entirely instead of reasons to pile on more. Chopping these
down into a pair of two-and-a-half hour movies would drastically improve the
pacing even if you didn't address the characterization or the tone issues.
You could leave around three hours of slow-motion action sequences, goblin
chases, and Radagast the Brown on the cutting room floor! Sounds great,
doesn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couldn't have said it better myself.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Legos "For Girls"</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2014/12/legos-for-girls/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-17T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-12-17T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2014-12-17:/2014/12/legos-for-girls/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://seasonaldepressioncomic.com/2014/12/06/lego-friends/"&gt;"This one weird trick that will make all Legos appeal to girls more"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So good. And so true.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://seasonaldepressioncomic.com/2014/12/06/lego-friends/"&gt;"This one weird trick that will make all Legos appeal to girls more"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So good. And so true.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Fix Linode Manager Repeated Log-out (Force IPv4)</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2014/11/fix-linode-manager-repeated-log-out-force-ipv4/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-25T13:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-11-25T13:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2014-11-25:/2014/11/fix-linode-manager-repeated-log-out-force-ipv4/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been having issues with Linode Manager repeatedly logging me out
every few requests. I figured this was related to ipv4/ipv6 switching, because
sometimes the logout would also trigger a new IP whitelist request, which would
sometimes be ipv4, and sometimes be ipv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little googling, I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been having issues with Linode Manager repeatedly logging me out
every few requests. I figured this was related to ipv4/ipv6 switching, because
sometimes the logout would also trigger a new IP whitelist request, which would
sometimes be ipv4, and sometimes be ipv6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a little googling, I found &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/endrift/status/421774360035074049"&gt;this twitter conversation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
href="https://twitter.com/linode"&gt;@linode&lt;/a&gt; Manager keeps logging me out at
seemingly random intervals, especially when trying to do DNS management. Is
this a known problem?&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jeffrey Pfau (@endrift) &lt;a
href="https://twitter.com/endrift/status/421774360035074049"&gt;January 10,
2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"
charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out I'm not the only one experiencing this issue. So I decided to set up
&lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt; as one of the replies mentioned, and force Linode to a single ipv4
address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that these instructions are for OSX (and were tested on Yosemite, 10.10).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I installed &lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt; via &lt;a href="http://brew.sh"&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;brew install dnsmasq
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then, I followed the homebrew instructions to install &lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt; as a service to
start on startup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo cp -fv /usr/local/opt/dnsmasq/*.plist /Library/LaunchDaemons
sudo chown root /Library/LaunchDaemons/homebrew.mxcl.dnsmasq.plist
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, before we actually start the service, let's get our resolver in place.
OSX allows us to define resolve data for specific addresses using files in
&lt;code&gt;/etc/resolver/&lt;/code&gt;. Here is my &lt;code&gt;/etc/resolver/manager.linode.com&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="l l-Scalar l-Scalar-Plain"&gt;nameserver 127.0.0.1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Basically, we're telling the operating system to use our local DNS server
(provided by &lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt;) for lookups for &lt;code&gt;manager.linode.com&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also need to configure &lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt; to force &lt;code&gt;manager.linode.com&lt;/code&gt; to a specific
address. First, we need an IPv4 address to work with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# dscacheutil -q host -a name manager.linode.com&lt;/span&gt;
name: manager.linode.com
ipv6_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;2600&lt;/span&gt;:3c00::14
ipv6_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;2600&lt;/span&gt;:3c00::34
ipv6_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;2600&lt;/span&gt;:3c00::24

name: manager.linode.com
ip_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;69&lt;/span&gt;.164.200.204
ip_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;72&lt;/span&gt;.14.191.204
ip_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;72&lt;/span&gt;.14.180.204
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then, copy the example configuration into place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;cp /usr/local/opt/dnsmasq/dnsmasq.conf.example /usr/local/etc/dnsmasq.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and edit &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/etc/dnsmasq.conf&lt;/code&gt;, adding this line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;address&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/manager.linode.com/72.14.180.204
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, start &lt;code&gt;dnsmasq&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo launchctl load /Library/LaunchDaemons/homebrew.mxcl.dnsmasq.plist
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Assuming you did everything right, you should only see one address when you
query again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;dscacheutil -q host -a name manager.linode.com
name: manager.linode.com
ip_address: &lt;span class="m"&gt;72&lt;/span&gt;.14.180.204
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I haven't done much on Linode since implementing this fix, but haven't had it
log me out erroneously once yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have improvements or run into issues, please leave a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Blog Auto-Publish with Dropbox</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2014/11/blog-auto-publish-with-dropbox/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-23T03:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-11-23T03:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2014-11-23:/2014/11/blog-auto-publish-with-dropbox/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I moved my blog over to &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; from
&lt;a href="http://octopress.org"&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;. I've been very happy with this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I decided I wanted to go a step further, and set up autopublish. I knew it
could be easily done with a git hook, but I wanted to be able to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I moved my blog over to &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; from
&lt;a href="http://octopress.org"&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;. I've been very happy with this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I decided I wanted to go a step further, and set up autopublish. I knew it
could be easily done with a git hook, but I wanted to be able to easily blog
from my iOS devices as well, so I decided to go with &lt;a href="https://db.tt/PNs6kv5z"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;
instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Getting Dropbox&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I needed to install Dropbox on my machine. Dropbox provides &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/install?os=lnx"&gt;an easy
one-liner&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ~ &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; wget -O - &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;https://www.dropbox.com/download?plat=lnx.x86_64&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; tar xzf -
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, when I first tried to start up dropbox, it gave me a cryptic error, which
I traced back to not having X11 libraries installed. Turns out I just needed
to unset my DISPLAY variable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;unset&lt;/span&gt; DISPLAY
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now Dropbox will start properly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;~/.dropbox-dist/dropboxd
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions to get Dropbox authorized on your server, then once
you see the success message, exit using ctrl-c.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Configure Dropbox as System Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we need to create an init script for Dropbox. I found an example
&lt;a href="http://www.dropboxwiki.com/tips-and-tricks/install-dropbox-in-an-entirely-text-based-linux-environment#Running_on_system_startup"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Here's the Ubuntu/Debian script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ch"&gt;#!/bin/sh&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#dropbox service&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;DROPBOX_USERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;user1 user2&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;DAEMON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;.dropbox-dist/dropboxd

start&lt;span class="o"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Starting dropbox...&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; dbuser in &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DROPBOX_USERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="nv"&gt;HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;getent passwd &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; cut -d: -f6&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -x &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DAEMON&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class="nv"&gt;HOME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; start-stop-daemon -b -o -c &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; -S -u &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; -x &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DAEMON&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="k"&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

stop&lt;span class="o"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Stopping dropbox...&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; dbuser in &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DROPBOX_USERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="nv"&gt;HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;getent passwd &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; cut -d: -f6&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -x &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DAEMON&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
           start-stop-daemon -o -c &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; -K -u &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; -x &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$HOMEDIR&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DAEMON&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="k"&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

status&lt;span class="o"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; dbuser in &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$DROPBOX_USERS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="nv"&gt;dbpid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;pgrep -u &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt; dropbox&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -z &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbpid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;dropboxd for USER &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;: not running.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
           &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;dropboxd for USER &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbuser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;: running (pid &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$dbpid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;)&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class="k"&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; in

   start&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
       start
       &lt;span class="p"&gt;;;&lt;/span&gt;
   stop&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
       stop
       &lt;span class="p"&gt;;;&lt;/span&gt;
   restart&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;reload&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;force-reload&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
       stop
       start
       &lt;span class="p"&gt;;;&lt;/span&gt;
   status&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
       status
       &lt;span class="p"&gt;;;&lt;/span&gt;
   *&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Usage: /etc/init.d/dropbox {start|stop|reload|force-reload|restart|status}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class="nb"&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;esac&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="m"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Note that when I pulled down that script originally, it had a typo. The DAEMON
line near the top of the file should be &lt;code&gt;.dropbox-dist/dropboxd&lt;/code&gt; -- they left
off the trailing &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; in the version I downloaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place this script in &lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d/dropbox&lt;/code&gt;. Replace the &lt;code&gt;DROPBOX_USERS&lt;/code&gt; setting
with a space-separate list of users for which you want Dropbox running. Then,
make the file executable and set it to execute on startup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo chmod +x /etc/init.d/dropbox
sudo update-rc.d dropbox defaults
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, start Dropbox again, as a service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo service dropbox start
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Selective Sync (Optional)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a very large Dropbox folder, and so only want to sync the Blogs folder
from my Dropbox account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded the CLI script mentioned on that installation page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;wget https://linux.dropbox.com/packages/dropbox.py
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then, with Dropbox running, I excluded all the directories within the Dropbox
folder, then removed the Blogs folder from the resulting exclusion list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;./dropbox.py exclude add ~/Dropbox/*
./dropbox.py exclude remove ~/Dropbox/blogs
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Perfect, now I have only my blogs syncing to my server's dropbox folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Autopublish: The Watcher Script&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The automagic regeneration of my blog I modified from &lt;a href="http://code.zoia.org/2014/02/25/pelican-dropbox-automatic-blog-regeneration/"&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to assume you have a working Pelican setup. Assuming you used the
Pelican quickstart, you should have both a &lt;code&gt;pelicanconf.py&lt;/code&gt; and a
&lt;code&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/code&gt; is going to be what we use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you must modify your &lt;code&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/code&gt; file such that it can operate from
any directory, rather than relying on relative paths. Thus, you should add your
blog's absolute directory to the Python path inside of that script. Here is my
&lt;code&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ch"&gt;#!/usr/bin/env python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# -*- coding: utf-8 -*- #&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;__future__&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;unicode_literals&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# This file is only used if you use `make publish` or&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# explicitly specify it as your config file.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;#sys.path.append(os.curdir)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# This is the directory where your pelican&amp;#39;s&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# configuration files reside&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;pelicanpath&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pelicanpath&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;os&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;curdir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;pelicanconf&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;SITEURL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;http://blog.basepi.net&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;RELATIVE_URLS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="bp"&gt;False&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;FEED_ALL_ATOM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="bp"&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;CATEGORY_FEED_ATOM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="bp"&gt;None&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;DELETE_OUTPUT_DIRECTORY&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="bp"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;These are the key lines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pelicanpath&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;sys&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;append&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pelicanpath&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now no matter what my current working directory is, the &lt;code&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/code&gt; will
be able to find the files it needs to operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I created a publish script, &lt;code&gt;publish.sh&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ch"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;PELICAN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/usr/bin/pelican
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;CONTENT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/content
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;OUTPUT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/output
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;SETTINGS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/publishconf.py

rm -rf /home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/output/*
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$PELICAN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$CONTENT&lt;/span&gt; -o &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$OUTPUT&lt;/span&gt; -s &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$SETTINGS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$?&lt;/span&gt;
rsync -r --delete /home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/output/ /var/www/blog.basepi.net
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Note the use of &lt;code&gt;|| exit $?&lt;/code&gt;. This will cause the script to exit if the retcode
of the pelican command is non-zero. I don't want to publish my blog if there
are problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make this script executable, and then run it to test that things are working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step is to set up the watcher script which will run our publish
script on changes. For this purpose we will be using &lt;a href="https://github.com/splitbrain/Watcher"&gt;this watcher
script&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script, conveniently, is ready to be used as an init script. Take &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/splitbrain/Watcher/master/watcher.py"&gt;the
script&lt;/a&gt; and put it at &lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d/watcher&lt;/code&gt;. Make it executable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo chmod +x /etc/init.d/watcher
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, we need to create the configuration file for the watcher. This file is at
&lt;code&gt;/etc/watcher.ini&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;DEFAULT&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; where to store output
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;logfile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/var/log/watcher.log

&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; where to save the PID file
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;pidfile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/var/run/watcher.pid

&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;job1&lt;span class="o"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;watch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/content
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;events&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;modify,create,delete,move
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;excluded&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;recursive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;autoadd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;command&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/home/basepi/Dropbox/Blogs/blog.basepi.net/publish.sh
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now we just need to start the watcher:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo service watcher start
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can tail the log to see if it's working (change a file to trigger it):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;tail -f /var/log/watcher.log
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If everything is in order, just have the watcher start on boot:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo update-rc.d watcher defaults
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And you're done! Now, any time you change the content of your blog, it will be
automatically re-built and published for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think in the comments. Or hit me up &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/basepi"&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="pelican"></category><category term="automation"></category><category term="tutorial"></category><category term="dropbox"></category><category term="blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Low Friction</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2014/11/low-friction/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-21T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-11-21T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2014-11-21:/2014/11/low-friction/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought that I had a pretty low-friction setup with my new blog on Octopress.
However, that was not the case. This morning I decided I needed to get my blog
back up. There have been a few times in the last couple of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought that I had a pretty low-friction setup with my new blog on Octopress.
However, that was not the case. This morning I decided I needed to get my blog
back up. There have been a few times in the last couple of years that I wished
I had it available. However, I didn't have any of the dependencies set up on my
new laptop. So I set out to get ruby installed and ready to generate my blog
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an hour of fighting &lt;code&gt;rbenv&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bundle&lt;/code&gt;, I decided it was finally time
to take the plunge, and switch to a Python-based tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, and had it generating my new site
from the default skeleton in a few minutes. Granted, I've had to take some more
time choosing a theme and porting my content over. But grand total it's only
taken me an hour or two of tinkering, and should reduce my blogging friction
substantially, both on new machines and on existing setups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did port over most of the content from my old blog. I may delete some of it
going forward, mostly out of embarassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lost my old disqus comments -- since there was only one comment on my old
blog, I decided it wasn't worth the potential hassle of making sure it
translated cleanly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the RSS feed is new, so you'll have to &lt;a href="/rss.xml"&gt;resubscribe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here we are, on the newest edition of
&lt;a href="http://blog.basepi.net"&gt;blog.basepi.net&lt;/a&gt;. Hope you like it.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>I'm Back!</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2013/09/im-back/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-13T23:32:00-06:00</published><updated>2013-09-13T23:32:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2013-09-13:/2013/09/im-back/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, at long last I got around to re-installing Ruby on my machine, updated
Octopress, and got my blogs settled.  I'm back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what's been going on in the interim?  Let's hit the top two:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I graduated Magna Cum Laude from the University of Utah with a BS in Computer …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, at long last I got around to re-installing Ruby on my machine, updated
Octopress, and got my blogs settled.  I'm back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what's been going on in the interim?  Let's hit the top two:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I graduated Magna Cum Laude from the University of Utah with a BS in Computer
  Science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I switched jobs -- I now work for Salt Stack, Inc, making awesome open source
  software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot has changed, and I hope to have much more to blog about now that I'm more
involved in the open source community.  Feel free to throw me feedback!  I
don't pretend to be an awesome blogger.  =)&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Why I switched to Octopress</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2012/02/why-i-switched-to-octopress/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-02-09T18:33:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-11-22T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2012-02-09:/2012/02/why-i-switched-to-octopress/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update, Nov 2014: Since I wrote this blog post, I have ditched Jekyll and
Octopress (mostly because of the pain of setting up Ruby, not because of those
pieces of software themselves). This blog is still static, but is now generated
using Pelican, a Python project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update, Nov 2014: Since I wrote this blog post, I have ditched Jekyll and
Octopress (mostly because of the pain of setting up Ruby, not because of those
pieces of software themselves). This blog is still static, but is now generated
using Pelican, a Python project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I received an e-mail from the RSA Anti-Fraud Command Center.
It related to &lt;a href="http://blog.cmyers.net/"&gt;my personal blog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that your website cmyers.net has been hacked by a fraudster.  It
is now hosting a phishing attack against RBC.  Please remove the fraudulent
folders/files as soon as possible and secure your website as it has been
compromised.  Please note that it is possible that the fraudulent content is
embedded in your website's legitimate files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out the claim was in fact true.  There were new files in my wp-admin
folder for my wordpress install.  When I loaded these files in a browser, it
looked like the home page for a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been hacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out it's actually quite a common thing.  WordPress is a common (and
apparently quite easy) target for these types of hacks.  It comes down to a
combination of it's popularity, lack of really security-centric design, and the
fact that it's written in PHP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered a few options.  Do I take the time to properly harden my PHP5
install and reinstall wordpress?  Or do I change systems?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.errstr.com/"&gt;My friend Andrew generates his blog&lt;/a&gt; using jekyll.  &lt;a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a
"simple, blog aware, static site generator."  It's super-cool, check it out.
However, unlike WordPress, it doesn't have a bunch of built-in themes, or even
a theme directory that I could find.  You have to write your own CSS and HTML
templates, which it uses to generate the site.  But it generates an almost
completely static site -- the exception would be if you build in functionality
for &lt;a href="http://disqus.com/"&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments or put your Twitter roll in the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I was going to switch systems, static is what I was looking for.  The
resulting site is much faster than a WordPress site, and much more secure.  But
I didn't have the time, knowledge, or creativity to create a theme from
scratch, and porting my theme from WordPress would be a many hour project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter Octopress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I received a tweet from my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/#!/julio_menendez"&gt;Julio&lt;/a&gt; that said to check out
&lt;a href="http://octopress.org/"&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;.  It's built on top of Jekyll with built-in support for great
syntax highlighting, Disqus comments, social integration -- everything I was
looking for.  And a great default theme, which I could use as a jumping point
for my own.  I was sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest is history.  I'll spell out the details in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Minecraft!!!</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2012/01/minecraft/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-01-05T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2014-11-23T03:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2012-01-05:/2012/01/minecraft/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update, November 2014: These days, I'm hosting my own vanilla minecraft server
on Linode, using &lt;a href="http://www.mcmyadmin.com"&gt;MCMyAdmin&lt;/a&gt; for a web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.  I broke down and rented a Minecraft server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I had hosted a Minecraft server pretty successfully on my personal
web server.  The problem became two-fold …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Update, November 2014: These days, I'm hosting my own vanilla minecraft server
on Linode, using &lt;a href="http://www.mcmyadmin.com"&gt;MCMyAdmin&lt;/a&gt; for a web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.  I broke down and rented a Minecraft server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I had hosted a Minecraft server pretty successfully on my personal
web server.  The problem became two-fold:  it was a huge time-sink, as updating
all the plugins that I was running took a long time at each release.  Also,
while hosting the Minecraft server, my server would often become unresponsive,
requiring a restart.  This was unacceptable, as I also host a Teamspeak 3
server, an IRC bouncer, and multiple websites from my server.  I needed maximum
uptime!  So I finally shut down my Minecraft server for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now it's back!  OK, it's not the exact same server -- I didn't bring the
old world over.  I wanted a fresh start.  But it's a Minecraft server, and it's
all mine for the building!  OK, not all mine:  I want you to come too!  If you
already have a Minecraft account, post it in the comments so I can add you to
the user list.  (Otherwise you won't be able to build)  If you've never played
Minecraft, head on over to &lt;a href="http://minecraft.net"&gt;minecraft.net&lt;/a&gt; and buy the game.  Just do it,
it's worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My server is at mc.basepi.net.  Come and join us in building something awesome!
=)&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Slide Design for Developers</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/12/slide-design-for-developers/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-12-24T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2011-12-24T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-12-24:/2011/12/slide-design-for-developers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://zachholman.com/posts/slide-design-for-developers/"&gt;This is a great article&lt;/a&gt; by a guy over at &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; about slide design.  He
makes some really good points, and his slides &lt;a href="http://zachholman.com/talk/how-github-uses-github-to-build-github"&gt;really are beautiful&lt;/a&gt;.  I
want to see more presentations with these design pointers in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://zachholman.com/posts/slide-design-for-developers/"&gt;This is a great article&lt;/a&gt; by a guy over at &lt;a href="https://github.com/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; about slide design.  He
makes some really good points, and his slides &lt;a href="http://zachholman.com/talk/how-github-uses-github-to-build-github"&gt;really are beautiful&lt;/a&gt;.  I
want to see more presentations with these design pointers in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>More on SOPA and Protect-IP (Don't break the internet!)</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/12/more-on-sopa-and-protect-ip-dont-break-the-internet/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-12-22T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2011-12-22T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-12-22:/2011/12/more-on-sopa-and-protect-ip-dont-break-the-internet/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More on SOPA and Protect-IP (Don't break the internet!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in my previous post, SOPA (the Stop Online Piracy Act) and Protect-IP
are both very bad pieces of legislation.  They are not only technically damning
for the internet, but they are unconstitutional.  When I started doing my due …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More on SOPA and Protect-IP (Don't break the internet!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in my previous post, SOPA (the Stop Online Piracy Act) and Protect-IP
are both very bad pieces of legislation.  They are not only technically damning
for the internet, but they are unconstitutional.  When I started doing my due
diligence the other day with regards to these bills, I didn't know much about
them.  After some research, though, I have discovered just how bad these bills
are.  Here's some more information, in a &lt;a href="http://www.popularmechanics.com/science/mythbusters/articles/mythbuster-adam-savage-sopa-could-destroy-the-internet-as-we-know-it-6620300"&gt;post by Adam Savage&lt;/a&gt; (from
MythBusters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That article is not that technical and doesn't really quote the bills much.
For the full story on the bills and just how technically bad they are, as well
as how unconstitutional they are, read &lt;a href="http://www.stanfordlawreview.org/online/dont-break-internet"&gt;the Standford Law Review's take on the
bills&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These bills are being pushed by the entertainment industry pretty hard, and not
necessarily for bad reason -- piracy is an issue. But these bills are
technically stupid, won't actually solve anything (the second link addresses
this -- it would just force piraters to use alternate services from DNS, which
is just bad for the internet at a whole and won't stop their activities), and
puts the US on a slippery slope towards censorship like Iran or China.  The
bills are being fought by every single major tech company.  (And probably all
the non-major tech companies as well -- they're just not as visible)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave your thoughts in the comments.  And speak up to stop SOPA and Protect-IP!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Stop SOPA (Stop Online Privacy Act)</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/12/stop-sopa-stop-online-privacy-act/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-12-19T18:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2011-12-19T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-12-19:/2011/12/stop-sopa-stop-online-privacy-act/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've heard a lot of chatter about SOPA (the Stop Online Privacy Act), which is
currently going through congress.  However, today I finally decided to look
into it.  And I definitely didn't like what I found.  Here's a video summing up
the problems (the video is for the Protect IP …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've heard a lot of chatter about SOPA (the Stop Online Privacy Act), which is
currently going through congress.  However, today I finally decided to look
into it.  And I definitely didn't like what I found.  Here's a video summing up
the problems (the video is for the Protect IP act, which was introduced earlier
this year, but most of the same problems apply to both bills).  (Found via
&lt;a href="http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/internet-censorship-sopa/"&gt;Matt Cutt's Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/31100268?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0"
width="400" height="225" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen
mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
href="http://vimeo.com/31100268"&gt;PROTECT IP / SOPA Breaks The Internet&lt;/a&gt; from
&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/fightforthefuture"&gt;Fight for the Future&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a
href="http://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch the video.  Then Google "SOPA" for more information.  You can also sign a
petition against the act &lt;a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petitions/%21/petition/veto-sopa-bill-and-any-other-future-bills-threaten-diminish-free-flow-information/g3W1BscR?utm_source=wh.gov&amp;amp;utm_medium=shorturl&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shorturl"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Visit &lt;a href="http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/internet-censorship-sopa/"&gt;Matt Cutt's Blog Post&lt;/a&gt; for some
more links to information and ways you can get involved.  Join with me and so
many others in speaking out against SOPA!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Android vs. iOS</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/11/android-vs-ios/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-11-01T18:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2011-11-01T18:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-11-01:/2011/11/android-vs-ios/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My iPhone 4S came this last week.  Previously, I was a proud owner of the HTC
Evo 4G, a great phone.  But still I switched.  Since I've had a few people ask
me why, I decided I'd better just blog it.  Sorry for my rambling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both platforms have their advantages …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My iPhone 4S came this last week.  Previously, I was a proud owner of the HTC
Evo 4G, a great phone.  But still I switched.  Since I've had a few people ask
me why, I decided I'd better just blog it.  Sorry for my rambling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both platforms have their advantages.  I suppose I'll go platform by platform
and examine some pros and cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;iOS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With iOS 5, an iPhone was finally a valid alternative to my Android phone.
Previously, I never would have switched, because of the lack of a good
notifications system.  If a push notification came in, it would interrupt
whatever you were doing, sometimes to the effect of restarting your progress
in a game or something.  This in and of itself was an annoyance, but could be
overlooked.  The main problem was that once a notification popped, if didn't
immediately go to that app and take care of it, it was gone.  Poof.  You
couldn't decide to leave this or that notification for later, because they
weren't being stored anyplace.  That all changed with Notification Center in
iOS 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was basically just a modified copy of Android's version of notifications,
which they got right from the beginning.  Drag from the top of the screen and
you have a list of all the notifications which you have not yet acted upon.  In
my opinion, Apple did it even better than Android -- you can define the order
in which notifications are shown manually, or you can have it based on the time
of the notification.  You can also act on the notification straight from the
lock screen by sliding-to-unlock using the notification icon.  (Hard to
explain, ask someone with an iPhone to show you if you don't know what I mean)
It's a pretty schweet feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things iOS has going for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very stable (rarely crashes, almost never have to reboot, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very clean (everything is hardware accelerated, so every action is smooth out
of the box)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher resolution screen than most Android phones, even the ones with bigger
screens.  People complain about the screen size on iPhones, but you don't even
notice because of how clear the retina display is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More secure (all apps are sandboxed, making malware pretty much nonexistent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More polished apps (I don't know why this is the way it is -- perhaps because
of Apple's app store policies, but apps are so much polished on average.  It's
true of both OSX and iOS)  This is a huge one.  The general level of quality,
both of games and of daily-use apps, is much higher on iOS than on Android.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better hardware, with very little fragmentation.  You have great battery life,
on every iPhone.  It's very compact for its power.  You almost never have to
worry about your phone not meeting "minimum requirements."  This is probably a
large part of what makes the previous statement (polished apps) true --
developers can focus on the quality of the app, rather than focusing on making
the app work for hundreds of different phones.  You're also guaranteed to get
all the iOS updates for at least a couple of years, something which 99% of
Android users do NOT get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great camera.  Yes, some Android phones also have great cameras, but many of
them are pretty much junk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone is a pretty great phone, but it does have some cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited customization.  Can't replace the stock keyboard, very few homescreen
customization options, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sandboxed apps.  This is both a pro and a con.  Apps can't really interact
because they're sandboxed.  You also don't have a file system in the classic
sense, which makes it more limited for a computer replacement.  Most people
don't care about this con, but it's still there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are the only cons I can think of right now, leave a comment if you find
one I missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Android&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Android is also a great platform.  I love Google, and love their products.
Things Android has going for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same type of notification system, tried and true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tons of customization options.  There are many great options for homescreen
apps which can change the look and functionality of your homescreen and app
drawer drastically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separation between homescreen and general apps.  This means you can use your
homescreen more like the desktop on your computer, with only apps you use often
showing there, and the rest hidden in the "app drawer," which you can open at
will from your homescreen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True multitasking.  This means that apps can run in the background and perform
tasks without being open, which is very uncommon in iOS, which utilizes push
notifications.  However, it can have performance and battery ramifications,
which we will explore in the cons section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apps have more freedom.  This means that you can have Google Voice, for
example, seamlessly integrate with the phone app, as opposed to being separate.
It also allows problems like malware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated menu and back buttons.  This is both a pro and a con, but I find
myself missing a dedicated back button on iOS, and having these buttons as
hardware buttons saves space on the screen which would be taken up by these
buttons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better integration with the Google-sphere.  Since everything I use is
Google, (Gmail, Calendar, Contacts, Voice, Talk), having this integration is
really nice.  You can get pretty decent integration in iOS, but it takes more
setup and is not as seamless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instability.  I had to restart my phone every few days because it would become
unresponsive or strange bugs would rear their heads.  A pain when your phone
takes a few minutes to restart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliance on phone manufacturer for operating system updates.  This is a big
one -- unless you've rooted your phone and are using custom roms, most OS
updates either never come, or are 6 months to a year late, and by then a new
version has been released.  This also causes problems with app requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inconsistent hardware quality.  Another big one.  Most Android touch screens
are not as precise or as quick to respond as the iPhone screens.  In addition,
some of the Android phones are cheaply made, and/or have really bad battery
life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True multitasking.  Like I said, this is a pro and a con.  The con is that a
frozen or buggy app can rampage in the background, sucking battery power and
processing power.  Even the ones that don't act up can continually such battery
life in the background.  In addition, apps are much harder to kill on Android,
since you have to go into system settings and wade through the list of apps to
do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Malware.  Without Apple-esque restrictions on apps, there is much more danger
of malware.  This is becoming an increasing issue as Android becomes more
popular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower app quality standard.  We've visited this already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary and Other Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to switch from one of the better Android phones to an iPhone 4S.  And
unless something big changes in the future, I'll never go back.  The stability
and polish is important to me, as is battery life.  I also will get the newest
versions of iOS right as they are released for at least a few years, where
Android users are often left out in the cold when new versions of Android come
out.  What you get will depend on what's most important to you.  But even as a
power user, I chose iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a recent article on the subject: &lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/scitech/2011/10/26/iphone-4s-vs-android-phones-whats-better-for/"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry for my rambling, be sure to leave a comment below with your opinions.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>More on Python</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/08/more-on-python/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-01T18:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2011-08-01T18:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-08-01:/2011/08/more-on-python/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My good friend &lt;a href="https://profiles.google.com/u/0/106066712316258581810/about"&gt;Chad&lt;/a&gt; recently started learning about Python.  After getting
a fair bit into a book on the subject, he posted on &lt;a href="http://plus.google.com"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language seems cool, though I haven't found a compelling reason to need it. I
think Django is the main reason I want to use it. Calling …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My good friend &lt;a href="https://profiles.google.com/u/0/106066712316258581810/about"&gt;Chad&lt;/a&gt; recently started learning about Python.  After getting
a fair bit into a book on the subject, he posted on &lt;a href="http://plus.google.com"&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language seems cool, though I haven't found a compelling reason to need it. I
think Django is the main reason I want to use it. Calling upon the powers of
+Julio Carlos Menendez and +Colton Myers to give me some examples where using
Python is WAY better than another language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to try to collect some of the research that I found while selecting
Python as my latest language-of-choice, and post it here.  Hopefully it will be
helpful to anyone who's trying to decide if Python is worth picking up.  Be
aware, though, this is going to be more a random collection of thoughts and
links rather than a linear blog post on the awesomeness of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose one of the first things I should point out, before we get into any
language specifics, is the community.  I love the Python community.  Whether
it's the mailing list(s), or the #python channel on Freenode, the community is
very active and very helpful.  In fact, the #python channel is one of the most
active on my IRC client.  With all that help available, solving problems
becomes much less daunting than in other languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Indentation as Syntax&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most immediately obvious things people notice about Python is the
significance of whitespace.  This is in contrast to most every other modern
programming language, and often throws people when they first discover it.  I
think of this part of Python as a very positive &lt;em&gt;feature&lt;/em&gt; of the language:
having indentation as part of the actual &lt;strong&gt;syntax&lt;/strong&gt; of the language makes for
very consistent code -- across almost every Python program, control structures
look the same, because the indentation delimits code blocks, rather than
braces.  If this feature seems weird or unnatural to you, I suggest you try
writing in Python for your next project -- the initial "weirdness" of this
feature rapidly fades away, and if you're like me, you find yourself
appreciating the innate readability that it gives Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intuitive Language Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this next section, I'll quote an &lt;a href="http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/3882"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; by Eric Raymond, where he
details his early experience with Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second [surprise] came a couple of hours into the project, when I
noticed (allowing for pauses needed to look up new features in &lt;em&gt;Programming
Python&lt;/em&gt;) I was generating &lt;em&gt;working&lt;/em&gt; code nearly as fast as I could type. When
I realized this, I was quite startled. An important measure of effort in
coding is the frequency with which you write something that doesn't actually
match your mental representation of the problem, and have to backtrack on
realizing that what you just typed won't actually tell the language to do
what you're thinking. An important measure of good language design is how
rapidly the percentage of missteps of this kind falls as you gain experience
with the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're writing working code nearly as fast as you can type and your
misstep rate is near zero, it generally means you've achieved mastery of the
language. But that didn't make sense, because it was still day one and I was
regularly pausing to look up new language and library features!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first clue that, in Python, I was actually dealing with an
exceptionally good design. Most languages have so much friction and
awkwardness built into their design that you learn most of their feature set
long before your misstep rate drops anywhere near zero. Python was the first
general-purpose language I'd ever used that reversed this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've experienced this myself -- Python's design is such that it works much more
fluidly with the solutions as they live in my head.  I can just start coding
and the solution flows easily from my brainwaves to working Python code.  Try
it, I think you'll be surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on the topic of Python's intuitiveness, I think we should talk about
IDEs.  C# is one of my favorite languages.  Using Visual Studio, you can create
very advanced and full-featured GUI applications on Windows with relative ease.
However, they key part of that last statement is "Using Visual Studio".  I find
when I'm writing in Java, C#, Objective-C, etc, I end up relying heavily on
intellisense to help me recall syntax and method names.  In contrast, Python is
designed so intuitively that I find that I am able to write full-featured
programs with only Vim and a few trips to the Python documentation to refresh
the name of a certain function within a certain module.  I think that's another
testament to the great design of Python, and just how intuitive it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, though C# can be used to create great Windows GUIs, Visual Studio
is again used to abstract away thousands of lines of GUI code which is
generated by Visual Studio as you code the GUI.  Have you ever tried to write a
C#, Java, or Objective-C GUI in a non-IDE text editor such as Vim?  It's nigh
unto impossible, because the syntax is so verbose and not intuitive enough to
easily remember.  Contrast this with Python's Tkinter toolkit, which allows one
to create GUIs with relative ease, and with no reliance on an expensive IDE.
And the Python GUIs look native on each platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Java vs. Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might as well throw in a side-by-side comparison of Java vs. Python.  Shows
some of the differences in verbosity and complexity between the two languages,
even if only in small examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://pythonconquerstheuniverse.wordpress.com/category/java-and-python/"&gt;Java vs. Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously Python is not perfect.  There are definitely downsides to having a
completely dynamically-typed language like Python -- if you're not careful, you
can have difficult-to-find bugs crop up.  And the task at hand can sometimes
require the speed of C, for example, or features from other languages -- Python
is not a cure-all, and I don't pretend that it is.  But for me, it's pretty
close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it comes down to is that I've come to really enjoy programming in Python,
finding it intuitive, straightforward, and full of features that make my job
easier as a programmer.  And I hope that it treats you as well.  =)&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Vim -- why???</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/07/vim-why/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-03T05:59:00-06:00</published><updated>2011-07-03T05:59:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-07-03:/2011/07/vim-why/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim is a 20-year-old text editor, based on the 35-year-old "vi" editor
(pronounced vee-eye, not vie).  vi and emacs are both part of an editor holy war
that has been going on for decades.  I discovered this holy war years ago,
mentioned on some website or another …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use vim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim is a 20-year-old text editor, based on the 35-year-old "vi" editor
(pronounced vee-eye, not vie).  vi and emacs are both part of an editor holy war
that has been going on for decades.  I discovered this holy war years ago,
mentioned on some website or another, and started to research.  I tried both
editors briefly, and then decided to take vim's side of the holy war.  At the
time, this pick was kind of arbitrary -- I really didn't know enough about the
two editors to make a truly educated decision.  I think I saw vim as the
underdog in the war, and as the more interesting of the two editors, with it's
strange idea of separate modes for text entry and for commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've never looked back.  When I first picked up vim, it was mainly so I'd have
bragging rights that I could program in a crazy-old terminal editor.  However, a
few years later and I do everything I can to work in vim as exclusively as
possible, whether for school, work, or personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often comment on my choice.  Why am I not using the feature-rich IDEs
available for the language in which I'm coding?  Why am I using such an &lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt;,
out-dated piece of software?  (This question just shows ignorance -- the latest
version of vim, 7.3, was released Aug 2010)  What's so great about vim?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's what this article is about.  Just as John Beltran de Heredia did in his
&lt;a href="http://www.viemu.com/a-why-vi-vim.html" title="Why vi/vim?"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;, I'm going to try to break some of the misconceptions surrounding
vi/vim, and show you why vim is king.  For those who already are convinced and
are looking for some vim resources, jump to the resources section at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Normal vs. Insert Modes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time you try vi/vim without any real introduction to it, the result is
almost always the same.  First, there's the disgust that you feel when you find
out that to even enter any text, you have to hit 'i' to enter insert mode.  The
normal and insert modes of vim are probably its most misunderstood feature, and
what makes vim so powerful.  But misunderstood, the result usually is that you
get into insert mode, use the arrow keys to navigate around, and do everything
you can to stay in insert mode.  That's how we've been trained -- if we enter a
letter, that letter should appear on the screen.  So you stay in insert mode,
dink around for a few minutes, then throw your arms in the air, yell "What's the
point???  This is so stupid.", and then never come back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that this is not the way to use vim at all.  The key thing to
remember with vim is that you stay in normal mode almost all the time, entering
insert mode for &lt;em&gt;short bursts&lt;/em&gt; of typing text, only to return immediately to
normal mode.  John Beltran hits the concept on the head in the article I linked
to earlier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the remembering-the-mode problem just doesn't exist: you don't answer the
phone in insert mode to get back to vi and not remember where you were. If you
are typing text and the phone rings, you exit insert mode and then answer the
phone. Or you press '&lt;Esc&gt;' when you come back. But you never think about insert
mode as a mode where you stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain the philosophy behind this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commands in vi/vim are meant to be combined - 'd' means delete, 'e' means 'move
to end of word', then 'de' is a complete command that deletes to the end of the
current word (something like Ctrl-Shift-Right, Left, Del in most regular
editors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you compare 'de' to the 'Ctrl-Shift-Right, Left, Del' in most regular
editors, you start to see the beauty of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, inserts are considered commands as well.  If you type 'i'
to begin inserting text before the current character, type a word or two, and
then hit 'Esc', that entire operation is a command.  This is important to
remember because of another key piece of functionality:  the '.' key.  When in
normal mode, the '.' key will repeat the last complete, combined editing command
you executed.  This could be the 'de' command we mentioned earlier, or it could
involve inserts.  For example, if you typed 'iHello&lt;Esc&gt;', then it would insert
the word "Hello" before the starting location.  Then, if typed a '.', it would
repeat that operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing is that you can also add a number argument before almost
any command (whether movement command or editing command), and that command will
be repeated that many times.  All these concepts can be combined to result in
incredibly flexible editing power.  Jon Beltran does a good job of a more
in-depth exploration of the power of vim, so I'll link you over to &lt;a href="http://www.viemu.com/a-why-vi-vim.html" title="Why vi/vim?"&gt;his
article&lt;/a&gt; again if you want to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Go Explore!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim is generally known for it's very steep learning curve.  I won't deny, the
learning curve is definitely there.  However, I will say that if you can stick
with it, you'll never regret it.  Vim key bindings allow you to basically ditch
your mouse, as well as carpal-tunnel inducing crazy key bindings for basic
operations.  Everything is at your fingertips, and it's so powerful!  You can
also find vim emulation plugins for many modern IDEs, such as Eclipse, Visual
Studio, etc.  Another interesting fact is that the default shortcut keys in
Gmail are vim-inspired!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you really want to try to learn vim, head over to Jon Beltran's site and get
his &lt;a href="http://www.viemu.com/a_vi_vim_graphical_cheat_sheet_tutorial.html" title="vi/vim Graphical Cheat Sheet"&gt;vi/vim graphical cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt;.  I found this invaluable as I learned
vim.  You'll also find many good books on vim.  Just follow the reviews on
Amazon or a similar site, and you'll find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have the basics down, you can start exploring ways to extend and
customize vim.  You'd be amazed to find out how truly customizable it is.  In
fact, if you're interested, &lt;a href="http://github.com/crakdmirror/dotfiles" title="Colton's dotfiles"&gt;check out my dotfiles!&lt;/a&gt;  This is a collection
of my various configuration files, including my vim configuration files.  I've
tried to comment everything thoroughly enough that you'll be able to follow
what purpose each command serves, but feel free to use the issue tracker to ask
questions!  You can even fork the repository (it's on Github), and modify to
suit your needs!  It's designed to be cross-platform (it requires one small
change in the .vimrc to define the platform), so it should be pretty easy to
incorporate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.viemu.com/a-why-vi-vim.html" title="Why vi/vim?"&gt;Why vim is the "Killerest"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.viemu.com/a_vi_vim_graphical_cheat_sheet_tutorial.html" title="vi/vim Graphical Cheat Sheet"&gt;vi/vim Graphical Cheat Sheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://github.com/crakdmirror/dotfiles" title="Colton's dotfiles"&gt;My dotfiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd love to add to this list of resources, so if you have a good one, leave a
comment!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Python: My Language of Choice</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/07/python-my-language-of-choice/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-01T18:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2011-07-01T18:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-07-01:/2011/07/python-my-language-of-choice/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently found a "poem" about the philosophies of Python.  It pretty well
embodies the reasons behind my recently acquired love of Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Zen Of Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful is better than ugly.&lt;br&gt;
Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;br&gt;
Simple is better than complex.&lt;br&gt;
Complex is better than complicated.&lt;br&gt;
Flat is better …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently found a "poem" about the philosophies of Python.  It pretty well
embodies the reasons behind my recently acquired love of Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Zen Of Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful is better than ugly.&lt;br&gt;
Explicit is better than implicit.&lt;br&gt;
Simple is better than complex.&lt;br&gt;
Complex is better than complicated.&lt;br&gt;
Flat is better than nested.&lt;br&gt;
Sparse is better than dense.&lt;br&gt;
Readability counts.&lt;br&gt;
Special cases aren't special enough to break the rules.&lt;br&gt;
Although practicality beats purity.&lt;br&gt;
Errors should never pass silently.&lt;br&gt;
Unless explicitly silenced.&lt;br&gt;
In the face of ambiguity, refuse the temptation to guess.&lt;br&gt;
There should be one—and preferably only one—obvious way to do it.&lt;br&gt;
Although that way may not be obvious at first unless you're Dutch.&lt;br&gt;
Now is better than never.&lt;br&gt;
Although never is often better than &lt;strong&gt;right&lt;/strong&gt; now.&lt;br&gt;
If the implementation is hard to explain, it's a bad idea.&lt;br&gt;
If the implementation is easy to explain, it may be a good idea.&lt;br&gt;
Namespaces are one honking great idea -- let's do more of those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This poem was actually immortalized in Python's &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0020/"&gt;PEP 20&lt;/a&gt;, where the abstract
reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long time Pythoneer Tim Peters succinctly channels the BDFL's guiding
principles for Python's design into 20 aphorisms, only 19 of which have been
written down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who might not be familiar, BDFL stands for Benevolent Dictator For
Life, a title which belongs to Guido van Rossum, the creator of Python.  PEPs
are Python Enhancement Proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the lingo out of the way, we can talk about the language
itself, and how I was introduced to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had spent a fair number of hours fighting to write shell scripts to handle a
few tasks on my web server.  After tearing a few handfuls of hair out in
frustration, I shot an e-mail to my good friend Andrew, who works as a
programmer and sysadmin for a local company.  He told me that he avoid shell
scripts where possible, writing scripts instead in Perl.  I had heard of these
so-called scripting languages, Perl, Python, and Ruby being the most prominent
in my mind, so I decided to look into them.  I did a lot of research into these
languages, and eventually settled on Python, primarily because of the
principles in the poem above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These principles just completely jive with my thoughts on programming.  Python
is designed such that most people that haven't ever written any Python code can
read it and understand what's going on.  Some have referred to Python as
executable pseudo-code, and it's almost true!  I found a quote which supports
the idea of human-readability in code perfectly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Programs must be written for people to read, and only incidentally for
machines to execute."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--Abelson &amp;amp; Sussman, &lt;em&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one of the many reasons for which I chose Python as the language I
would attempt to master.  Another was the community -- the #python channel on
Freenode is almost never quiet -- there are always people asking for help with
some issue or another, and always people there to answer.  I'm sure there are
similar communities with Ruby and Perl, but so far I really like the community
that comes with Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing that surprised me as I continued to learn about Python is that it is
much more than a scripting language -- it is powerfully object-oriented, and
even has very powerful GUI toolkits such as &lt;a href="http://wiki.python.org/moin/TkInter"&gt;Tkinter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep discovering more and more exciting things as I continue to learn about
Python, and look forward to leveraging it's power more in my own personal
projects.  Now I just need to slowly work at getting it introduced at work...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's your language of choice, and why?&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>...and again.</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/04/and-again/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-02T18:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2011-04-02T18:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-04-02:/2011/04/and-again/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Here we go again.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, seriously.  You've gotta be wondering, "Why does he even keep trying?"
This has to be my 6th or 7th attempt at a blog.  Shouldn't I just give up
already?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this time I'm trying something a little bit different.  I'm going to blog
about …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Here we go again.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, seriously.  You've gotta be wondering, "Why does he even keep trying?"
This has to be my 6th or 7th attempt at a blog.  Shouldn't I just give up
already?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well this time I'm trying something a little bit different.  I'm going to blog
about technology, rather than my personal life.  Obviously I'll try to throw
some personal life stuff in there, but the problem is, I don't feel like my life
is interesting to write about, and thus I have a hard time staying interested in
the writing, and I assume others have a hard time staying interested in the
reading.  Those of you who aren't "techies" out there, I hope you'll still come
read a little.  I think you'll find some interesting stuff.  And who knows, if I
can keep up interest in a tech blog, maybe I'll be able to make and keep a
personal blog too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More to come.  I'm going to post a little on the reasoning behind this post a
little later.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Always and Forever...</title><link href="https://basepi.github.io/2011/04/always-and-forever/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-01T18:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2011-04-01T18:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Colton Myers</name></author><id>tag:basepi.github.io,2011-04-01:/2011/04/always-and-forever/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned in the last post, I'm taking a little bit of a different
approach with this blog. Rather than try to blog about my life, which, in my
opinion, leads to rapid loss of interest both on my part and the part of my
readers, I've decided to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned in the last post, I'm taking a little bit of a different
approach with this blog. Rather than try to blog about my life, which, in my
opinion, leads to rapid loss of interest both on my part and the part of my
readers, I've decided to focus on something that I'm actually interested in
(and I hope interests a few of you):  technology.  Specifically, computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got pulled in at a pretty young age.  First it was the computer games -- &lt;em&gt;Load
Runner&lt;/em&gt; on our black-and-white Macintosh; later, &lt;em&gt;Warcraft 2&lt;/em&gt; on our 486.  It
just escalated from there.  I still play a lot of video games (my parents will
tell you that I play way too much, and they're probably right), but the less...
flashy end of computing pulled me in, slowly but surely, as time went on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Dad taught me some basic DOS commands as we installed Doom from about nine
floppies.  I learned how to install and uninstall programs, tweak the operating
system to gain more performance, mess with the registry enough to need a Windows
reinstallation... (not very hard, that last one -- but a rant on the Windows
registry should be a topic for another day)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded tool after tool, tinkering with different things.  I discovered the
editor wars (Vim vs. Emacs), and decided I wanted to take a side in that war.
(Vim, by the way.....it's where I'm editing this article right now!)  I
eventually took a large course in C# and Java my senior year in high school, and
that's when the fun really began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along this journey I discovered a few things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to build a computer from components means nothing.  Anyone who
  claims they're computer-savvy because they built their own computer is naïve
  and generally &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; computer-savvy at all. Computer-savvy people know that
  building computers means basically nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody knows everything about computers.  It's true.  This ties in nicely with
  the previous point in that if someone claims they know everything about
  computers, they probably know next to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Computer genius" is not defined by the knowledge you have -- it's defined by
  the ability to successfully find, interpret, and apply the information needed
  to solve a problem.  99% of the time, any problem you're having has been
  solved by someone else.  Finding that information is an art, however.  Anyone
  can type things into Google.  But how many people do you know who always find
  the answer they're looking for from Google?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point is, I don't claim to know everything.  In fact, I generally know just
enough to (1) be dangerous, and (2) have an idea of how much I do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; know.
But I do know a few things, and hope to be able to share some of them.  I also
hope to be able to learn a few things in turn from you, the reader.  So please,
comment!  I love questions, and I'll do my best to find the answer for you, and
I love it when people give new ideas/tricks, or yes, even when they correct
errors in my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's get to it!  =)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS:  Now that you know the topic of this post, props to whoever can guess the
reference in the title.  Party on.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>